Total Experience: 13 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: MS/M.Sc(Science) [Information

Notice Period: 15 Days or less

systems]

Venkata Ramana Badri (1) Featured

Senior Software Engineer seeking assignment in Software Development using Java, J2EE, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Webservices, Hibernate, Java Script, Jquery, Angular ,oracle ,MS SQL,Kafka message server and apache tomcat and ready to join immediately



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer

Current Company: Qumu Corporation

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Software Application Development, Requirement Gathering, Software Design, Software Coding, Software

Testing, SQL Developer, J2Ee, Spring Boot, Spring Mvc, Apache Tomcat, MS SQL Server, Oracle, JSP

Servlets, Javascript, Angularis

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Summary

I have over 13 years of experience in design, development of Software applications using Java/J2EE, Spring MVC, Hibernate and REST web services,

PL/SQL programming, Oracle, MySQL, MS SQL, Java Script, HTML, Dojo JS, Jquery, IHUB report, analytics reports designer, Kafka message system,

Jboss, Apache Tomcat and BEA Web Logic servers

Well versed with Junit, Jacoco, Sonarqube, Eclipse, OpenText Analytics Designer, JIRA and SQL Developer

Versatile team player with quick learner, good communication, interpersonal & analytical skills.

Work Experience

Qumu Corporation as Senior Software Engineer Nov 2017 to Till Date

Qumu as Senior Software Engineer

Nov 2017 to Oct 2020

Involved in design, development, testing and code reviews using Java, Spring MVC, Spring Webservices, Java Script, MS SQL, Tomcat, Opentext Analytics reports and MS SQL data base server

Qumu as Senior Software Engineer Nov 2017 to Oct 2020

- Involved in analysis and design of Services for admin/viewer portals,
- Involved in coding and testing of the services,
- Involved in design and development of reports using Opentext analytics designer,
- Involved in Unit Testing and documented all the activities,

Persistent Systems & Solutions, as Team Lead

Nov 2009 to Nov 2017

- Involved in analysis and design of Services for APIs,
- Involved in coding and testing of the services,
- Involved in Unit Testing and documented all the activities,
- Conducted code reviews as per the standards given.

Birlasoft as Senior Software Engineer Oct 2008 to Apr 2009

- Involved in developing EJB, JSP & Servlets coding confirms to the java coding standards adopted by Organization
- Conducted code reviews as per the standards given.
- Involved in Unit Testing and documenting all the activities.

Polaris Consulting and Services Ltd. as Associate Consultant

Oct 2007 to Oct 2008

- Involved in developing EJB, JSP & Servlets coding confirms to the java coding standards adopted by Organization
- Conducted code reviews as per the standards given
- Involved in Unit Testing and documenting all the activities.

Crenesis Software Solutions, as Software Engineer

Aug 2006 to Sep 2007

- Involved in developing EJB, JSP & Servlets coding confirms to the java coding standards adopted by Organization
- Conducted code reviews as per the standards given
- Involved in Unit Testing and documenting all the activities.

Education

UG: BCA (Computers) from Andhra University in 2002

PG: MS/M.Sc(Science) (Information systems) from Andhra University in 2004

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Certification in SCJP1.5 (Suncertified Java Programmer 1.5)

Certification in Developing SQL Databases-762

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
PL/SQL programming			
Java, Spring MVC, Hibernate		2020	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
REST Web Services			
Oracle ,MySQL and MS SQL			
Java Script, HTML, Dojo JS and Jquery			
kafka message system		2020	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Junit, Jacoco, Sonarqube, Eclipse		2020	13 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
JIRA and SQL Developer			
ihub reports	16	2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
AngularJs	8	2020	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Telugu				

Projects

Project Title: Qumu VCC Client: Qumu Corporation

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Dec 2017 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Role: Other

Team Size: 5

Skill Used: Spring Restful Web services, Hibernate 4, Open text analytics ihub, Oracle, MS Sql and Apache Tomcat server Role Description: Sr. Software Engineer

Project Details: Qumu is a leading provider of complete end-to-end Enterprise Video solutions. Large and mid-sized businesses choose Qumus video platform to capture, manage, and distribute live and on-demand content with total reliability and security. This end-to-end approach to high quality video management assures that enterprises can readily adapt to dynamically changing business needs. At the core of the system is the Video Control Center (VCC). VCC provides features such as a content repository, publishing workflows, a social video portal, Pathfinder for optimizing video delivery and permissions-based access.

Project Title: Trinet Client: Trinet

Duration: Dec 2015 - Nov 2017 Nature of Employment: Full Time

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: The client TriNet provides HR solutions to small and mid-sized businesses. TriNet administers payroll and health benefits and advises clients on employment law compliance and risk reduction. TriNet's HR products cover the core services of payroll, benefits, risk & compliance, HR team and a cloud platform. TriNet partners with more than 10,000 clients in a variety of industries to provide HR solutions.

TriNet provides multiple HR products tailored to specific industries. Each bundled HR product includes TriNets core services: payroll, benefits, risk & compliance, an HR team and cloud platform. TriNet passport is one of the product.

Project Title: Intellect Invest Brokerage Client: Development Bank of Singapore Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Oct 2007 - Sep 2009 Role: Other Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Skill Used: EJB, JSP, Servlets, Hibernate, AJAX, Oracle & WebLogic

Role Description: Senior Developer

Project Details: The Intellect Invest is a part of Intellect Suite of products and is a highly customizable wealth management solution. The Intellect Invest is identified as GenS (Generalized Service) and spans off into four broad modules, Intellect -Mutual Funds, Intellect - Special Products, Intellect - Brokerage and Intellect - Blotter.

The Intellect Invest - Brokerage product, a part of the Intellect suite of products, is a back office and retail brokerage solutions system that enables banks to offer brokerage distribution services for their retail clients. The system works as an independent product processor and needs to interface with other products/systems, from the Intellect suite or other third parties, for accessing the cash accounts and credit information.

Project Title: Vidya Client: SNIST, Hyderabad Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Aug 2006 - Sep 2007

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 5

Skill Used: Struts, Servlets, JSP, Oracle and Weblogic

Project Details: This is an ERP system for all kinds of educational Institutes. This helps in maintaining the records right from admissions to the alumni of the institute. This provides complete transparency in the maintaining of the institute by providing all the information online. Details like the attendance, marks, conduct, assignments, calendar etc can now be seen online. Also, for a more down trodden parents who do not have access to computer or internet, all the details will also be sent as an SMS to their mobile phones on a frequent basis. The main actors for this project are administrator, teacher & student. the system provide no of facilities like college calendar setting ,Timetable Management, Courses Management, Marks Management, Examinations Management, Library Management, Salary Management, Attendance Management, Leave Management and Message Management System.

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time